Bye bye!
Bye bye, Kobato.
See you on Monday!
I'm sorry!
Why you... Every single time...
Are you ok?
Fine, just move outta the way. I'm going to be late.
Are you going to another job?
Yeah.
Kobato! Thank you for your hard work.
Is there anything else I can help with?
I'll be okay here. You can go home now.
Part Time Jobs
Help Wanted Information
Kobato.
How do I do this again?
The simplest things in life
end up being the most difficult.
I just want to smile when I'm happy
and sing a song whenever I please.
I was told, "Someday,
your dream will come true."
But when exactly will that be?
I can't wait that long!
I spread my arms
on the count of one two three
and gather all the light in the world.
Tell me,
isn't there something I can do?
Even if someone hurts my feelings,
I'll keep running toward the light.
Even if I trip, fall, and cry my eyes out, I still believe.
Although it may seem silly...
I believe in tomorrow.
Production
The Kobato Protection Group
...Detective Kobato Hanato.
There are so many different kinds of part time jobs, aren't there?
What are you going to do with that book? Oww.
Get a job of course! Just like Fujimoto.
'Cause you wanna help pay back even
just a little of the nursery's debt, right?
Right!
Maybe I could deliver newspapers bright and early in the morning!
Don't you oversleep every morning?
Well then...
How about delivering pizza to people's houses?
You're definitely the type who would get lost.
Oh... well then...
How about helping people move?
You'd just break things and make a mess in general.
Then what kind of job should I do?
Don't ask me!
I give up!
Ioryogi?
Hello?
Yes?
He has a rip!
Poor doll.
Sorry about this.
Don't worry about it.
Here you go, all done.
Thank you so much!
No problem.
Actually, there's something else I wanted to ask you...
European Style Sweets   Tirol
The umbrella person!
Oh, you're the one from...
Thank you so much for the other day.
Don't worry about it.
Oh, you already know each other?
Yes.
It's nice to formally meet you. I'm the manager, Ueda.
I'm Kobato Hanato!
Kobato is a tenant at my apartment and
she always helps out at Yomogi Nursery.
She said she was looking for a place to work and your shop came to mind.
I see.
It's very busy here so if she could work even just on the weekends, it'd help me out immensely.
At least until my hands heal.
They're in bad shape right now...
What happened?
I'm really clumsy, see...
She hurt herself just recently.
Are you all right?
Yes. But when it gets busy here, it's hard for the manager to take care of everything himself...
We'll be counting on you then, Kobato.
Yes, I'll do my best, Manager!
And, umm...
I'm Yumi Omura. I look forward to working with you, Kobato!
Good luck, Kobato!
Thank you!
I finished changing.
The uniform fits perfectly! I'm so glad.
And now, what should I do to help?
Well... First, when a customer
arrives, be sure to greet them.
Welcome!
Yes, just like that...
Got it!
And when you get an order, put the cake inside one of those boxes over there.
These, right?
I'll be working the register, so when the customer pays, make sure you say...
Thank you very much! Right?
Yup.
Welcome.
Welcome!
Let's try, shall we?
Okay!
I'll have... a shortcake and a Mont Blanc... and...
Shortcake and Mont Blanc...
Not a cheesecake, but... an apple pie... and a lemon tart!
Cheese, apple... lemon?
Umm...
And a cream puff please.
Uhh...
Shortcake, Mont Blanc, apple pie, lemon tart, and a cream puff.
You're amazing, Yumi!
Now, put those in a box, Kobato.
Right!
Umm, shortcake and—
I'm sorry!
It's okay, calm down. Get a different one.
Okay.
Kobato, are you okay?
Y-Yes.
And now a Mont Blanc and...
An apple pie and a lemon tart. And a cream puff.
I did it!
Then when you're all finished...
Thank you very much!
Thank you as well, Miss Cheerful Shop Attendant.
Was that okay?
Yup. Once you get used to it, I'm sure you'll be great.
Welcome!
Huh?
Kobato!
It's Marina and her mother!
Welcome!
Hello there.
Kobato works in a cake shop!
Yup! Today I'm working in this cake shop.
That's so cool.
What kind of cake would you like?
We came to pick up my birthday cake today!
It's your birthday?
Happy birthday!
Kobato, come wrap this up for her.
Okay!
Here you go.
I got it!
Here you are. Sorry for the wait!
Thank you, Kobato!
Thank you very much!
See you later!
Huh?
What's the matter?
Happy Birthday Marina
Why is this...?
It must've been switched by accident...
I'll go see if I can catch Marina!
Marina!
Are you okay, Kobato?
Y-Yes...
Welcome!
I'll have this one and this one please.
Okay!
Ah Kobato, this customer ordered
the Mont Blanc and the cheesecake.
I'm sorry!
I'm so tired.
Kobato, you did well today.
You were wonderful, Yumi.
Here you go, a present for you.
Thank you so much!
Ioryogi will be so happy!
Io...?
He looks like a stuffed animal to everyone right now.
We'll be counting on you tomorrow as well.
I can come in tomorrow too?
Yes, of course.
Yumi, you can go home now too.
But what about cleaning?
I'll handle it. Your hands haven't
healed yet, don't overwork yourself.
Okay.
Then I'll be going, Manager—
I'll be heading off now, good night!
Thank you, and good night!
Is something the matter?
Huh? Oh, no, it's nothing...
But you look like you're
worried about something...
I'm just thinking about the manager...
About the manager?
It seems like he's worried about something...
I asked him about it once, but he said nothing was wrong.
I see...
I mean, the store is doing well and everything...
Then I wonder what he could be worried about.
Do you think it could be loans?
Yomogi Nursery is having a
problem paying back its loans.
Is that why you started working at Tirol?
Yes.
That's so nice of you...
Not at all. Both Fujimoto and Miss
Sayaka work so much harder than I do.
That's why I hope that I can help them out even just a little bit!
Me too... I wish I could help out the manager.
This is really good.
It must be painful to want to help
someone but not being able to do anything.
I'll find out what's bothering the manager!
I guess that's fine.
But if you do something
wrong, you might lose the job.
And then I won't be able to eat this delicious cake.
But then again... You could
always work at other places.
Sushi    Shop
At a sushi shop!
At a steakhouse!
A high class Chinese restaurant!
Kobato, what kind of job are you gonna get next?
I'm going to continue working at the bakery!
Good morning!
Good morning, Kobato.
Good morning.
Could you line these cookies up on the shelf?
Okay!
All right, then I'll leave it to you.
Did the manager just look at me and sigh?
He did?
I wonder why...
Does whatever the manager is worried about have something to do with me?
I'll go and ask what's bothering the manager.
Leave it to me!
Really?
Could you just casually ask him what's the matter then?
Yes! I'll try my best!
Excuse me?
Kobato?
Yes... Actually...
There's something I wanted to casually ask you!
Kobato...
What is it?
Are you worried about something?
No, there's nothing. I'm fine.
But Yumi said that it seems like there's something on your mind,
like there's something on the tip of your tongue...
You've just been kinda strange lately!
It's nothing that Yumi needs to be worried about.
And that's what he said.
But that just makes me even more concerned.
Welcome.
Oh, Kobato?
Miss Sayaka!
What are you doing here?
She's helping out here until my hands heal.
I see.
Are you here to buy a cake?
I'm going to visit Chitose; I thought it'd be nice to buy her a little something.
It's been a while since I've
gotten anything from Tirol.
If I remember correctly, you ordered a birthday cake for your husband here before, right?
Right...
Miss Sayaka's... husband?
The man she got married to.
But I've never seen him before.
Well, maybe they broke up.
Miss Sayaka seemed very lonely...
This isn't something you can just ask about directly, okay?
How come?
There are some things people just don't want to talk about.
You're hiding the fact that you're working part time to help the nursery, right?
People don't just go about telling others everything.
I wonder if the manager at Tirol is the same way...
But Yumi really wants to know...
What should someone do in that situation?
See if they can investigate secretly I guess.
That's something that you're not suited for though, Dobato.
But I'll still try my best!
Thank you very much!
This is definitely... secretly I suppose.
It's Kobato!
What are you doing?
I'm doing a secret investigation!
So cool!
You're like a detective!
Detective?
So this is a detective!
Yup. That's right!
They investigate a lot of things, don't they?
Like motives and alibis and evidence...
And they do searches and get information and tail people!
That's so cool!
We'll help too!
No, a detective acts alone!
Is that so?
Somehow, this has gotten completely off track.
Thank you very much.
Excuse me!
I'm being a detective for today and...
Detective?
Did you notice anything strange at Tirol?
No, not really...
Has there been some sort of incident?
Yes! The "manager is troubled" incident!
The manager?
Is troubled?
Would you happen to know anything about this?
Asking us really won't...
Anything at all?
The cakes at Tirol are really popular...
I can't think of anything outside of work-related matters.
I see...
Thank you very much.
W-We'll be on our way then.
I can't deal with this anymore.
I'll do my own dragnet.
Dragnet?
What?!
You think I'd accept something like that?
Stingy, aren't you, Genko.
If this is about love advice,
take your business elsewhere!
Well then, I'll be taking my
present and leaving I guess.
You just came to eat my baumkuchen, didn't you!
Oh, someone's angry.
What did you say?!
See ya.
Thank you for today.
Yumi!
Kobato?
Hello!
What are you doing?
Detective work!
The things I've discovered so far are:
Tirol's cakes are very popular,
and the manager's worries are probably work-related.
I've also found out that the manager always gives out chocolate to little children,
asks about people's health,
and that the people all love the
cakes made by the nice manager.
I even managed to get
some chocolate by accident.
The manager really is nice to everyone isn't he?
Yumi, this is the part where we tail him!
Kobato, it's fine, we should stop.
Let's go back.
But...
Huh?
I wonder if he's waiting for someone.
I know it's wrong to follow people like this, but...
Someone's here!
I wonder who she is...
You don't know her?
Not at all.
Is this... a date?
That's probably why he couldn't tell me about it.
Kobato, what should I do?
Calm down, Yumi!
We'll be noticed!
Yumi?
Yumi!
Wait!
Manager?
Kobato!
Are you okay?
I'm fine.
But the person that you were just with...
I was actually... interviewing...
A new employee for the store...
A new employee?
Why?
Kobato is able to come and help out on the weekends now...
But I've never been able to give you any time off, Yumi.
Time off?
I was afraid that you were really tired,
and I was thinking that you
got injured because of that...
Manager...
So that's what you were worried about?
Yes.
You always work so hard,
so I felt that I was taking advantage of you...
And I felt terrible about it...
I do it because I like working together with you.
I don't care if I don't get time off!
I like seeing the happy faces of the
customers who come and buy Tirol's cakes,
and I like being able to see you everyday!
And... my injury is because...
Um...
It's so pretty!
You... made this?
Yes...
I've been learning how to make cakes. That's why I have so many injuries.
Easy to Make Cakes
Cake Ma
Cak
I wanted to help you out, even just a little, so I've been studying...
I'm sorry I didn't tell you.
Do you mind if I try it?
O-Okay.
It's delicious.
Really?
I've managed to hire a new employee for the store,
so from now on, let's devote time to practicing making cakes together.
Okay!
What, you actually managed to solve things?
Yes! Detective Kobato, case closed!
The manager wanted to make sure Yumi had time off to rest...
Yumi wanted to be of more help to the manager...
It was a beautiful case in which the two of them were only thinking of the other.
That's good I guess.
I got to eat more baumkuchen.
That baumkuchen isn't from Tirol, is it?
And before, you brought
back a present, didn't you?
I wonder if that present has
something to do with your dragnet?
Uh, that's right! Your score for this time, Kobato!
You get a sweet 100 points because I got to eat cake!
Really?
Fujimoto!
What?
I have a present for you!
It's chocolate from the store that I'm working at now.
Work? You?
I'll work hard too, so you try to rest a little and go to college.
You working hard isn't exactly music for my ears.
Meanie...
Hey.
Don't push yourself too hard and collapse or something.
Could you possibly be worrying about me?
Absolutely not.
Thank you!
Whatever, do something about that writing on your face.
This is my 100 points!
What are you talking about? It's just a scribbling, isn't it?
No it's not!
You only get 50 points because you're a meanie!
I don't get you at all.
Even though we all want to fly,
we're being deceived by gravity.
In reality, everybody can already fly.
The reason why that child looks so sad
might be because she left her shadow somewhere.
If so...
If telling you "Thank you",
or hearing "Thank you" just makes you smile,
then doing those things will make me happy.
Next episode of Kobato will air next year January 5
And they'll make you happy too.
Don't worry, we're together.
It's mysterious as to why tears roll down
even though I'm happy.
Next
...Silver Eyes.